<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Bruno Hensel</title><link>https://www.brunohensel.dev/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Bruno Hensel</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 23 Dec 2023 14:41:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.brunohensel.dev/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Partially-applied function, a `practical` example.</title><link>https://www.brunohensel.dev/posts/partially-applied-function-example/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Dec 2023 14:41:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.brunohensel.dev/posts/partially-applied-function-example/</guid><description>Partial application Link to heading In computer science, partial application (or partial function application) refers to the process of fixing a number of arguments of a function, producing another function of smaller arity. Source
The way I see it, this is a function in which the final result is computed at different time:
// Example from the Functional Programming with Kotlin book fun &amp;lt;A, B, C&amp;gt; partial1(a: A, f: (A, B) -&amp;gt; C): (B) -&amp;gt; C = { b -&amp;gt; f(a, b) } In this case, we call a function passing in as arguments a a:A value and a function from (A, B) to C, producing another function from B to C.</description></item><item><title>The Downsides of Excessive Mocks and Stubs in Unit Testing</title><link>https://www.brunohensel.dev/posts/down-sides-of-mocks-and-stubs/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Aug 2023 08:09:57 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.brunohensel.dev/posts/down-sides-of-mocks-and-stubs/</guid><description>The Downsides of Excessive Mocks and Stubs in Unit Testing Link to heading As commonly known, unit testing is a crucial part of software development. The use of mocks and stubs has become standard practice to isolate components and ensure reliable tests (London School). However, it&amp;rsquo;s imperative to recognize the fragility and potential pitfalls associated with excessive mock and stub usage.
Clarifying Mocks and Stubs: Link to heading Before delving into the drawbacks, let&amp;rsquo;s clarify the terms &amp;ldquo;mock&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;stub.</description></item></channel></rss>